Agent experience is an extension of
developer experience. You know,
developer experience, it's greater than
the sum of all of its parts. It's not a
question of whether or not agents are
working on your codebase or on your
platform. They are. The question is
whether or not you're supporting those.
But where we are today is this thing I
call this mini oneperson band problem.
So figure out what they're using. Figure
out what's working, what's not. And the
reality is if there is a gap in
knowledge, it will confidently make
things up or decide for you. To combat
this, context files are where you need
to spend your initial time. And if you
couldn't simplify something, make it
obvious. One practice that I really
enjoy doing is like an agent therapy
session. Like what should we do better
to make sure that you're going to get
this right next time? And specifically
update the context files to make sure
that happens. Ephemeral environments are
something I'm a huge fan of. At Netifi,
we do deployments like pre-prod
deployments or preview deployments and
they're amazing feedback tools [music]
for everything that's not specifically
code related. As Bon Scott said from
AC/DC, it's a long way to the top if you
want to rock and roll. It's a much more
enjoyable ride if you're with your
friends and with your band and you're
going together.
[music]
Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast's for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. All
right, back to the episode.
We have a second uh 30 minute keynote uh
before we jump into main tracks and
that's that uh next keynote is going to
be from Sean Roberts from Netifi who's
the VP of applied AI. Um now this is a
this is a really interesting session
because I think when we think about how
we have built software over time and we
think about our core kind of like ICP
when we when we build that software we
think about the user and the user being
very often a human a developer or or
just a consumer of our services but
times have changed with the adoption of
agents being you know so in our face
with everything AI it's important that
when we when we think about you know
providing these services providing these
these tools, we think about agents as
users of that as well as developers. And
so this session is really going to kind
of like compare the two and talk about
how we can plan with agents in mind as
our users. So uh please welcome on stage
Sean Roberts.
>> Thanks for that.
>> All right. Hello everyone. Um as Simon
said, I'm Sean Roberts. I lead the AI
programs at Netlefi. Um, [snorts] and
I've been working trying to make the web
better, more secure, faster for a very
long time. And especially at Netlefi,
I've been really trying to figure out
how we can provide the best agent
experience that we can for our platform,
but also trying to figure out how the
web and agents can work really well
together.
And so with that, you know, let's dive
into the talk today around agent
experience. And I don't know the makeup
of the crowd, but if you don't know what
this is referencing, that's not a me
problem. Um, you know, take a picture,
share with your friendly neighborhood AI
agent, and they will tell you it's
definitely in the training data. Um, but
really what we're talking about today is
how how agent experience is an extension
of developer experience. Um, a quick
raise of hands or or horns here. Um, who
is a senior plus dev or in charge of a
codebase today? A bunch of you. Yeah.
Horns. Yes. Uh, all right. Raise your
hands again if you feel like you are a
steward of the developer experience of
your codebase today.
Yes. Yes. All right. Well, thank you for
your service. Uh, this is often a very
thankless task. Um, but it's incredibly
important because um, as we know, you
know, developer experience really is the
sum. uh it's greater than the sum of all
of its parts, right? To have a great
developer experience, you really need to
have good documentation, onboarding,
there's intuitive design that goes into
it. It's an intentional act that you put
into it. Like, but the reality is is if
you're allowing people to develop on
your platform or on your codebase, you
have a developer experience. That does
not mean it's good. It just means you
have one. Just like every software has a
user experience if they have users.
And with agent experience, it's very
similar, right? Um we have hit this
critical mass where it it's not a
question of whether or not agents are
working on your codebase or or on your
platform. They are. The question is
whether or not you're supporting those.
And when we talk about agent experience,
we do mean that kind of holistic
experience that an agent has interacting
with your system or your codebase.
And to illustrate this, right, um again,
you know, when we think about developer
experience, we think about these
developers over here who are
handcrafting
beautiful error-free artisal code. It's
great. Um and and the the quality of
them going from here to here is really
determined by the quality of the
developer experience. And now we have
developers who are delegating work to
agents um to do parts of this on their
behalf. And when we talk about agent
experience, we're talking about this
connection here. So the how well are
they able to achieve you the same amount
of of work. Um, and and this connection
is all predicated on how well the agent
experience is.
And I think it's very important to
emphasize we're talking a lot about the
agents experience here, but this is all
to benefit the human developer on the
other side of it. This is nothing to do
with replacing developers. There are
developers delegating work to an agent.
And the more successful we can make
them, the more successful we can make
them, right? That's the whole point of
this. It's also worth noting that when
we talk about agent experience, we're
we're talking about it today in in
regards to a codebase, but an agent
experience is this discipline that spans
much broader, right? Um going forward,
e-commerce is going to have to figure
out how they serve their customers who
are using agents to buy on their behalf.
um flights, how how they you know book
flights and and airline tickets when an
agent was used to delegate. Um so it's
not specific to us but it's very
important as right now agents are best
at working with our code bases. Um but
as Guy described they are have a lot of
room for improvement. So one more time
who who's in charge of the developer
experience of their codebase here
yet? Oh, a lot left's hands. A lot of
people decided not to. But now, everyone
of you holding your uh your hands up and
probably everyone in this room really
you're also in charge of the agent
experience. It doesn't like maybe that
used to be a question mark before. It's
not anymore. Like it is a part of
serving developers is acknowledging the
fact that developers are using agents to
also work with your codebase. Um so you
have this charge. Now it's very
straightforward but um there there's
you know having an agent experience and
using agents isn't a new thing but where
we are today is this thing I call this
mini oneperson band problem like we've
all you know have gone off our teams
individually have gone off figured out
what works for them and they've kind of
culminated like kind of like their view
of the world and like they have their
whole setup right um and then two days
ago Gemini 3 came out and someone with
10 years of experience using
anti-gravity IDE said you should stop
what you're doing here and then switch
to this and so someone will and then now
your team kind of you know expands its
surface area and so forth and then you
know there's pro there's going to be
another tool next week and the next you
know a few weeks and and we get this
kind of sprawl we we have individually
went out figured things out and and
we've built this this is the kind of
mini oneperson ban problem that we see
with with developer AI native tooling
today.
How many of you have gone to a band
where there's like four or five of these
playing at the same time or go gone to a
concert there's four or five? Yeah, zero
of you because they can't. And but you
know because these are this is not a
band. These are three individuals maybe
trying to do their own thing. Maybe
towards the same end but this not a
band. Okay. Um [snorts]
this is a band. So a again ask your AI.
Um this is a band they they have
purpose-built um you know tools. They
are all trying to come together for the
same goal to to make um great
experiences for for their customers,
their audience, right? And that's really
important because together they're able
to do far more than any one person band,
right? Um, and you know, for those who
like the orchestra metaphor better,
there you go. Um,
all right. So, now what what is it that
we actually need to do in order to to
have a better agent experience um to to
improve the developer experience of our
code bases?
Um, and thankfully Guy did a lot of the
examples and homework for me earlier, so
that's awesome. Uh, but I'll dive into
the the other parts of it. I I think
what's really important for us to to
make sure that it's clear on is there's
no specific solution. I wish we could
say this, if you do this, you're done.
You know, pack it up, let's go home. Uh,
but there's not. Agent experience is a
discipline, not a specific tool. Okay?
And just so so if you're if you're
thinking about, okay, I have to support
agents, so I just need an MCP server.
that's all I need. Check the box done.
That's thinking far too narrowly about
this problem. And whether it's MTP, ADA,
ACP,
these are all solutions that are kind of
under under the umbrella of an agent
experience. Um, but the other reality is
we're all still figuring it out. We have
a lot of ideas about what works today
and then we're going to prove those
wrong tomorrow and then we're going to
keep iterating on it. But we're right in
the middle of it. And so where should
you actually start? So this is going to
be my recommendation around the kind of
crawl, walk, run stages that you can
take on to to start either start your
journey or expand it going forward.
So the first thing like if if your team
is just a bunch of one person bands um
or not doing any of this at all, start
with figuring that out, right? Like I
think that there's a hunch, yeah, my
team's using AI, whatever. Like like we
we're AI native. It's like, no, like
like figure out what they're using. Ask
them, figure out what's working, what's
not. And and this doesn't have to be a
big effort. Get a Google form, whatever,
vibe code it, and just ask them what
what agents are they using? What's
working well? And to be clear, don't ask
them the question that we asked them a
year ago, two years ago. We're like,
have you tried any agents? Like, no.
Like, everyone's probably tried an AI
tool, but we want to know is what people
are using every day or every other day.
What's working? what's not.
And it's important to understand that
for for many reasons, but not least of
which is the fact that there are lots of
AI agents and tools and combinations of
them. And then all the work that you're
going to be doing to um improve the
agent experience. This helps scope it
much better. Just understand what people
are doing. If they're using spec driven
development, that might be a little
different looking of an agent experience
than if they're using some some other
tool or they're really into stuff like
lovable or bolt, things like that.
So, audit audit what people are doing.
Figure out what's going on. Um, and then
start to build your internal community,
right? All that really, you know, has to
all that is really involved in doing
that is getting them together every, you
know, infrequently, but get them
together to talk about the issues that
they're running into. Talk about the
tools that they're using. Um, if you
really want to learn something cool,
come up with a problem or take something
some take some ticket off the board and
say, "Hey, I'm going to solve this
together and I'm going to watch you
solve it your way. I'm going to solve it
my way and we're going to we're going to
learn together." And that's some version
of of pair programming here. Uh where
there's also an AI agent involved and
that is so illuminating in terms of like
how what people understand differently
about the different uh the code base how
they approach the problem and and it
will also start to build up your
internal community um to to build
towards an agent experience.
So taking the next step forward, right?
Uh you know the agents that you need to
support
now you need to help them be better. Guy
did an a fantastic job of explaining
this for me earlier with with with some
data around backing up that uh the LMS
themselves are not sufficient in terms
of understanding your codebase. Um and
and the reality is is if there is a gap
in knowledge, it will confidently make
things up or decide for you. It's not
always made up false. It just might just
be totally different. Like his example
of picking a theme that was not the
right theme
um to combat this, right? Context files
are where you need to spend your initial
time, right? Um either you know
depending on the tools, right? agentsmd
files, steering files, cloud code, uh,
cloud files, cloudMD files. Um, these
are going to be very important um,
nuggets of information. And you know,
some rules of thumb that I think about
is if uh,
if you could if you couldn't simplify
something, make it obvious, right? So
many code bases you see like, okay, to
run a test suite, it's this some magical
command that you got to run. That's not
obvious. If if you have those, make sure
that they're in your context. Um
other areas are like if you have a
decoupled architecture. So you have a
front end um that's decoupled from your
backend which might be decoupled from
your your data layer etc. It doesn't
necessarily know those connections and
you need to make those clear or it will
make those connections it it'll make
them up every time. Um [snorts] and
that's going to be incredibly important.
Um and and and especially whenever you
get into this world of as people are
um iterating on this and they start
finding that
hey it's it something that we thought
was obvious wasn't it's going to keep
making those things up and adding those
into your um uh agents files and and
steering files is going to be incredibly
important.
The next thing I mentioned um is is the
core dependency uh documentation. I'd
mentioned the core dependency of the the
front end has a dependency on this back
end. It's over here. Here's how you use
it. Here's how you find information
about it. And that's incredibly
important, but there's also this this
problem of um dependency uh
documentation and like third party
modules, things like that, even first
party separated modules and and and guy
went in uh a lot of detail about that.
This has been bothering me for so long.
Um because you know the reality is
especially with you know brownfield type
of projects is
I I have developers or so the model is
trained on version one of my API the
latest version is version three but all
my developers are using version two and
so like it messes it up nine times out
of 10
>> [snorts]
>> um and and the the tooling for getting
this right isn't great today. I was
actually, you know, writing this, I was
very stoked to see Tesla's, you know,
registry and things like that that
they're doing. Um, and so I'm gonna
explore that more. I think that's very
exciting. I definitely agree that
there's actually, um, more onus needs to
be put on the open source community to
deliver these things. The way I kind of
see the Tesla registry is like, well, if
every uh, dependency had to have its
types hosted somewhere else, right? like
really the types, the documentation for
it really needs to be there. But we also
have the second problem where especially
open source repos
there's people who build on them and
then there's people who use them and
those are different documentation and so
like even it still gets a little bit
harder and harder the the more you try
to optimize but again we're all figuring
this out together so that's fine. Um if
if you use context 7 that's also
something that uh people people use. Uh,
I've I've run into issues with it not
doing very well on the versioning side
of things. Um, but regardless, if you
have a key dependency that's a third
party module,
make sure it's in your context. Make
sure you're using it right, especially
if it's things like data based
databased um uh because there's it's
just a such a dense topic and tool set
that um it ends up getting pretty
confused with those types of tools. So
make it clear and especially for very
large code bases um the concept of
knowledge graphs um there's many
different implementations of them
cognition released uh deep wiki and and
code maps recently but it's this you
know the reality is is if you have a
really large codebase and you're asking
it to do things every time that you try
to ask it to do something it's got to
kind of figure it out on its own and the
larger the codebase the longer that
takes the more expensive it is the more
likely is it's going miss parts or get
confused. And this is where knowledge
graphs really come in where you can kind
of pre-roduce
this kind of understanding of the
overall architecture, how things relate
to one another and summarize those. And
so before it tries to do things, it
consults there first. And those are very
helpful for larger code bases.
Uh feedback loops are going to be
incredibly important. Um, so if you're
if you're already getting your internal
community together, working with them to
say, "Look, whenever we're having an
issue, if if it if a human had to
manually intervene in an agent uh
agent's workflow, get that documented.
Get that into context." Um, if you're
talking to that senior engineer who's
been there for 15 years and has all the
tribal knowledge in their head, if you
every time you have to consult them, if
that doesn't go back in documentation or
context, I don't know what you're doing.
But like that that's this internal
feedback loop. You have to have some
forcing functions to make sure that your
agents understand because unlike you,
they they can't go ask uh necessarily
that that uh that tenure developer who
has all the information in their head.
So establish feedback loops with your
internal team. One practice that I
really enjoy doing is I have this MC MCP
where it's like, okay, if the agent's
really going off the rails here, um, I
have it look back and say, what could we
have done better here? It's like an
agent therapy session. Like, what what
should we do better to make sure that
you're going to get this right next
time? And specifically update the
context files to make sure that happens.
And then especially like once we do that
um assuming it makes sense at the time
having it try again and then go from
there. Uh I have a lot of good results
with that as well. [snorts]
I'm sure most of you if not all of you
are using AI review tools in in your um
uh code bases and your CI pipelines and
such. the so I won't go too deep into
that but like the one thing that I think
is an addition on top of that is not
only having your your uh AI review tool
figure out what's wrong with a thing but
also suggests when there are patterns
that were missing from your context
files that would have prevented this
from happening in the future. So like
this is you're getting towards the step
of trying to automate some of this
feedback loop.
Ephemeral environments are something I'm
a huge fan of. Um, you know, at Netlifi,
we can we we do deployments for like
pre-prod deployments or preview
deployments. Um, and we can do as many
of them as as the agent needs or as the
developer needs and they're amazing
feedback tools for everything that's not
specifically code related, right? Right?
So if it's like the style of a thing or
the layout of a thing, if it's just
making stuff up, you can both have the
the human review these things as or as
well as you know, if you want to give
access to the the agent to review these
things on your behalf. These really and
then combining these things. So an agent
figures out, okay, I messed up the
layout here. I'm going to go fix it. I'm
also going to make sure I document this
in the context. Now you're really
starting to see a this full end to end
picture. And this is ultimately what you
kind of end up with with with a good
agent experience and feedback uh life
cycle. So developers can delegate works
to to to the agents. They generate the
code and this again this being the the
agent experience that they have access
to here. They are better at doing this
because the feedback loop of making sure
the context is good um uh appropriate um
for for the jobs that they're doing and
so on. they can, you know, you have your
your reviewer agents figuring out, hey,
this should have been done differently.
I'm going to make sure that they know
that going forward. Um, I can also make
sure that they can review the the actual
changes, not just the code, but also the
the output of that code and and then
make suggestions for doing better going
forward.
Okay. And as we get into the um
you know you're really advancing your
your your the agent experience of your
codebase um shared sub agents is a
really cool unlock. So shared uh sub
aents these are going to be like guy
mentioned earlier um these are as simple
as just markdown files of defining hey
this is a specialized agent because by
default all these agents are generalists
right and as we know with full stack
developers they can get the job done but
a specialist is probably going to get it
done a at least a little bit better if
not completely better um these are your
specialized sub aents you define them in
a markdown file and then so you can say
okay This is our methodology for design.
This is our meth methodology for
copyrightiting. It has our voice and
tone in it. This is our data migrations
sub agent. This is they are specialized
at doing this. And what's going to be
really um
the the big difference that you're going
to see here is that when you ask it to
do something, you have sub agents. It's
going to say, "Oh, actually it's better
for this one to go do it." And it will
kick that one off. And it has
specialized contexts. Now imagine you
had five specializations that you wanted
to really hone in on and tune and you
had to throw all that context into a
single cla MD file or agents MD file.
That does not work well. And that's kind
of why we have these now. We figured out
that that doesn't work well. You
overload the context. It gets confused.
It starts to steal attention and and
things like that. So this is uh shared
sob agents are are very important and
and and really allow you to have a
shared way of doing things across your
code bases and across um your different
developers.
You have your context files, you have
your uh steering files, and now you have
uh sub aents files. You're immediately
going to run into how do I distribute
these things? Um because as soon as you
have more than one repo as as guy was
mentioning these things are are you know
there there are things that are repo
specific that always should be in the
repo and then there's going to be things
that are global. Your voice and tone for
your brand that's a global thing. Um
your brand styons all that stuff global.
How you might you know do reviews all
those things are global. Um, but how do
you share that across your your
developer base, which might be, you
know, dozens or, you know, potentially
thousands of people? Um,
and my my preferred methodology
personally is to centralize these things
into uh the globals into a shared repo
and then having a CLI that people can
run to update them and do that those
things. And um I also learned through
guys talk that they they have this
capability on the Tesla um platform as
well. But I think that once you like
this is a good problem to have. Okay,
we've defined rules. They're working
really well in our code bases. We
actually need to propagate this so that
we're working better across multiple
code bases. Um, and centralizing these
outside of a single agent as guy also
mentioned is incredibly important,
right? Because like if it doesn't like
like you did this audit step one, unless
they all said I only use cloud code and
they only all they all only use codeex,
then picking one agent is a recipe for
disaster. Also, if they're all only
using one agent, you you're probably
already setting yourself up for a future
problem. Um but uh yeah so so centralize
these um if you don't use a platform
like Tessle you can use centralized
GitHub repo that also has a CLI to run
to to do the syncs
and I think really on the bleeding edge
of of these uh optimizing your agent
experience um we we we have these
opportunities to run evals on the AX of
our of our code bases and if you haven't
used or done any um agent evals all they
really are are putting an agent under
certain conditions asking to do certain
task and evaluating the performance of
it doing those things
but have you ever considered taking now
cloud SDK or codeex SDK throwing that in
eval saying hey
try to do some stuff on my on my repo
and then help me figure out what I
should tell you to do that better you're
doing these things wrong um you know guy
and the Tesla team have done a lot of
this on the open source side of things,
but this um doing this for your own repo
is incredibly uh important, incredibly
validating.
It will really help you close the gaps
between what's just clear in your
documentation today and what's still
missing.
In addition to helping you fill gaps, it
also helps you solve the the the one-way
ratchet problem or it's a Asmov's law of
bureaucracy. I totally knew that before
yesterday. Uh
um which which says right like um laws
and regulations once they're enacted
monotonically just grow. They never
contract and they never substantially
get repealed or or or reduced. [snorts]
And we are seeing that happening with
config or with with context rules and
context as well. They're just growing.
We're like ah I missed this thing. I'm
going to keep adding to it. So, but how
do you safely feel confident in peeling
back some of those requirements and how
do you do how do you um you know you fix
this issue but you cause other issues.
How do you feel confident about not
doing that? And I think eval for for the
agent experience is going to be
incredibly important.
Um cool. So we covered a lot of ground
in terms of you know the developer
experience. We we all understand that's
our charge now. We're we're we have been
in charge of the developer experience
for our code bases, but agent experience
is no longer optional. That's a part of
what we have to deal with now. Um
[snorts] not because we want to support
agents, but because we want to support
our developers who use agents. Okay.
and making this I was really um stoked
on on using the band a whole metaphor
because I think what's really important
about bands is the size of them doesn't
uh determine the success of them, right?
It doesn't matter how big your band is,
but what does matter is how well they
can perform together and and produce uh
great outcomes. And so when we think
about all the things that we've heard
with like, oh, if you use these tools,
you'll be a 10x developer. So now we get
one one person band and this other 10x
developer wants to be their own
oneperson band. But what's really
magical is is having um
a 10x team, right? And that really comes
when when we're all sharing knowledge
and we're all working together. Um, I as
as the the as Bon Scott said from AC/DC,
um, it's a long way to the top if you
want to rock and roll, but I would amend
that to say it's a much more enjoyable
ride if you're with your friends and
with your band and you're going
together. So, with that, thank you all.
Thank you for coming here. Drink some
water. Go make good Adrian's grace.